Sesame seeds
芝麻
I'm drinking hot americano this morning
今天早上喝熱美式
Hi everyone, good morning, it's 8:53 am
嗨大家早安 現在是早上的8點53分
This week, I want to record what I eat in a week
然後這個禮拜呢我想要來錄
I'll film everything I eat for you to see
就我會把所有我要開始吃東西的時候會把它拍下來給你們看這樣
It is morning right now
現在是早上
I'll have some coffee first, I'm not too hungry yet
我先喝點咖啡我還沒有太餓
I don't have too much appetite
沒有什麼很有胃口
Today’s lunch is the broccoli pasta that I shared with you before
今天要做的午餐是之前跟大家分享過的那個broccoli pasta
Broccoli pasta
花椰菜義大利麵
Focus
就是那種 對焦
The ingredients are super simple, just prepare a type of noodle that you like
料超級簡單 就是準備一個你喜歡的麵
I'm using this noodle
然後我用的是這個麵
Then broccoli
然後花椰菜
And cheese, I'm using this kind of powdered cheese
然後cheese 我這邊用的是這種粉末的
It's better if you can buy the fresh one
如果你可以買到那種新鮮的更好
But because I don’t eat cheese that often
但是因為我沒有那麼常吃cheese
I'm afraid that if I buy the fresh one, it'll go bad if I don't use it
我怕買新鮮的它會很快就沒有用就發霉
So I'm using the powdered one instead
所以我就用這種粉的
And prepare some garlic
還有準備一些蒜頭
Then some oil, I'm using avocado oil here
然後一點油 我這邊用的是avocado oil
Then with this kind of chili pepper
然後跟這種辣椒
Dried chili pepper
這種乾辣椒
This is super easy, it only takes about 15 minutes
真的做超快大概15分鐘
The majority of the time may be used to cook the noodle
最長可能是在煮這個麵
Let me start prepping
那我來準備
(Stir-fried broccoli)
（炒花椰菜！）
(＋Water used to cook the noodle)
（＋煮麵水）
Cheese, add a lot of cheese
Cheese 要加很多cheese
It's going to burnt
要焦了
(Cheese pull~)
（起司牽絲～）
Super delicious
超級好吃
I ran out of cheese or I will add more
Cheese用完了不然我會加更多
A quick dish that I make for lunch very often! (I planned to pack it for lunch for the next day, but we finished everything)
中午超級常煮的快手菜！ （本來要帶隔天便當，結果直接吃完）
(Fruit vinegar)
（水果醋）
(Continue working!)
（繼續工作！）
I'm having beef noodle soup tonight
今天晚上吃牛肉麵
This is the beef that I marinated the day before
這是我前一天先滷好的牛肉
I took some marinade out to make the beef noodle soup
然後拿一些滷汁出來煮那個牛肉麵的湯
The side dish today is the Taiwanese kimchi I made myself
今天要配的小菜是這個是我自己做的那個台式泡菜
It’s cabbage pickled with vinegar, salt and sugar
就是高麗菜然後把它用醋還有鹽巴還有糖就是把它醃過一次
I also put some Sichuan pepper in it
我裡面還有放一點點花椒
The Sichuan pepper makes a difference, I tried it myself
就是有花椒有差喔我自己試過
Remember to add Sichuan pepper if you're trying next time
所以大家如果下次醃的話要記得加花椒
(Very excited in the background)
（背景音很激動）
Do you want to add chili in yours?
你的要加辣椒嗎
Today I'm adding the Laoluozi garlic chili oil
今天加那個老騾子蒜蓉辣椒
We're having beef noodle soup for dinner today
今天晚餐吃牛肉麵
And the Taiwanese kimchi that I made myself
然後我自己做的那個台式泡菜
Wow the beef today is super delicious
哇 今天牛肉超好吃
Do you want to add green onions or not?
你想要加蔥嗎 還是可以不用
Taiwanese Kimchi
台式泡菜
They go so well together
好搭喔
It's almost 9am now
現在是快九點
I want to make lunch
我要來做午餐
Today I'm eating this lobster that my friend recommended
今天是吃我朋友大推的這個龍蝦的這種
It's frozen lobster meat
他是那種冷凍的龍蝦肉
It's actually only 11am but I'm too hungry
現在其實才十一點但是我已經太餓了
Let me look at the instructions
先看一下這個怎麼做
Where is the lobster meat?
然後龍蝦肉在哪
Seasoning...
Seasoning...
Butter
奶油
(Very uncertain)
（很不確定）
Wow
Wow
So pretty
看 很漂亮
Assemble
組裝
I want to add a little bit of this sauce that I like a lot
我這邊想要加一點我自己蠻喜歡的這個是
This kind of Mexican style chili lime sauce
那個有點墨西哥口味的那種chili lime的那種醬
(It goes really well with chicken nuggets too!) It's a lime flavor
（搭配雞塊很好吃！） 就是他有點檸檬的醬的口味
It exploded
他爆出來了
Looks super delicious
看起來超好吃
Coffee
咖啡
(coffee time)
（咖啡時間）
This is Starbucks' nitro cold brew
這個是starbucks的氣泡cold brew
I bought this at Costco
這在costco買的
It's this kind of dried shiitake mushrooms
是那種香菇乾
It's good but a little too salty
很好吃但有點小鹹
I can’t eat a lot at a time
就是沒辦法一次吃很多
(I'll look for snacks in the afternoon when working from home) I’ll have a ferrero rocher
（在家工作下午都會翻零食吃！） 我吃個金莎好了
Isn’t it obvious that it’s a lot less than yesterday
是不是很明顯比昨天少了很多
I am eating this all by myself
但是這都我一個人在吃的
So pretty
怎麼那麼美啊
(Using my free time in the afternoon to make the side dishes for dinner)
（下午有空先來做晚上吃的小菜）
(Cucumber with preserved egg~)
（皮蛋涼拌小黃瓜～）
Minced garlic
蒜頭末
Depending on how much you want to add
然後看你想吃多少
I think American garlic is not too spicy and not too strong
我覺得美國蒜頭不太辣也沒有什麼很濃的味道
So I like to add a lot
所以我都加蠻多的
Then cover it
然後蓋起來
What?
幹什麼
My radish soup is almost ready
我的蘿蔔湯差不多已經煮到這樣
I already took a sip and it's really good
我剛已經偷喝了一口 湯已經超香
I am going to add some meatball now
然後我現在要來加那個貢丸
Tomato scrambled eggs
番茄炒蛋
(Side dishes made in the afternoon)
（中午做的小菜）
(First time making honey braised pork ribs)
（第一次做蜜汁排骨）
Wow it looks so pretty
哇 看起來好漂亮
Today's dinner is done
今天的晚餐完成
I'm having brown rice today
今天吃我吃糙米飯
Taiwanese kimchi and side dishes made in the afternoon
然後台式泡菜 下午做的小菜
And this is some sort of honey braised short ribs
然後這個是那種蜜汁排骨之類的東西
Stir-fried vegetables and tomato scrambled eggs
然後炒青菜 番茄炒蛋
And the radish pork ribs soup with meatball
還有今天煮的那個貢丸排骨蘿蔔湯
A bit salty
有點鹹
Good?
好吃嗎？
Wow this cucumber is delicious
哇這小黃瓜很好吃欸
Be careful, the chili pepper is very spicy
欸你要小心這個辣椒會辣
It's the kind of chili pepper that is actually spicy
他是那個真的會辣的辣椒
Preserved egg with cucumber
小黃瓜皮蛋
I should take pictures and send to my mom
欸我應該要拍給我媽看
Let me grab my phone
我拿一下手機
(My husband's lunch for tomorrow)
（先生明天中午的便當）
Bento
便當
Empty
清空
(Greek yogurt)
（希臘優格）
(While brushing my teeth haha)
（一邊在刷牙哈哈）
Oh so hot
嗚好燙
Good morning
大家早安
It's 9:18am in the morning
現在是早上的9點18分
I want to eat breakfast today
今天很想吃早餐
So I made some breakfast and want to eat it quickly
所以就弄了一些早餐想說可以快速吃一下
Can you see Nana?
你們看得到娜娜嗎？
Nana keeps looking at me from below
娜娜一直在下面看我
Nana
娜娜
What are you doing?
你幹嘛?
I feel that this avocado might be super ripe
感覺這酪梨應該超爆熟
Forgot to eat it
忘記吃它了
Hope it hasn't turned black
希望它不要黑掉
Is it crooked?
有歪掉嗎
Wow it's so beautiful and soft
哇好漂亮 而且超軟的
Okay
好喔
I want to make a small burrito today
今天想要做一個小捲餅
(Cilantro)
（香菜）
I always look at what leftover we have in the fridge
其實我都是看冰箱剩下什麼東西
Just throw in whatever I want to eat
就是把想要吃的東西丟進去這樣
Cilantro
香菜
I need to share this sauce with everyone
我一定要大分享一下這個醬
This is Nando's peri-peri sauce
這個是Nando's peri-peri sauce
Didn’t I go to live in Seattle for two weeks?
我前陣子不是去住在西雅圖 可能兩個禮拜多嘛然後
Our family friends over there recommended this
我們那邊的親戚就是親戚朋友就推薦說這個超好吃
So I bought it
然後我就買了
It's really delicious, it goes really well with fried chicken
就是真的很好吃 它就是超級適合搭那種炸雞
That kind of sauce
就是那種醬
This is the hot flavor, let me show you
然後我這個買的是hot的口味 我給你們看
I have another extra hot flavor
我還有一個extra hot
I'm so excited
所以我很期待
I will eat this hot one first
我先吃這個hot的
I will add this hot sauce
我來加這個辣醬
Wow it's so fragrant
哇超香
So delicious
超好吃
That sauce is so
那個sauce真的是
I wanted to give you a bite but I added cilantro
本來想給你吃一口但是我都有加香菜
What is this?
這是什麼 這是什麼
It's not in focus
它沒有對焦欸
Taiwan science noodles
科學麵
I realized that I also bought salted egg
發現我還有買一個鹹蛋
It's too delicious
太好吃了
I think the company that makes Taiwan scientific noodle is really smart
我覺得做科學麵的公司好厲害喔
Has this product been popular for over 20 years?
歷久 這產品已經紅了有沒有二十年了
Yes
有
I like to eat Taiwan scientific noodle in bigger pieces
我喜歡科學麵就是這種
Not in small pieces
就是不是所有都超小塊的
I'm going to start making dinner now
現在要來準備晚餐
I'm going to cut a lot of vegetable
要來切很多那個蔬菜
I'm making pork ribs now
我現在在煮排骨
And make it into pork ribs stewed with rice later
然後等一下要做排骨燜飯
(Pork ribs stewed with rice) We have too many pork ribs
（排骨燜飯） 太多排骨要消耗了
(Two dogs are home after a walk) Aloha
（二肥散步完回家） 阿囉哈
Wow this is so greasy
哇這個好油喔
The lotus root is ready
拍一下 蓮藕可以吃了
So good
好吃
Cut it
剪一下
I'm going to take a look at pork ribs stew with rice now
我現在要來看排骨飯
Wow it smells so good
哇好香喔
Looks super delicious
看起來超好吃的
I'm starving
太餓了
It smells so good
好香喔
So pretty
超美
Dinner is done
晚餐完成
This is the pork ribs stew with rice that I spent most of the time today making
這個是今天花最多時間做的這個排骨燜飯
Then here are the same side dishes as yesterday
然後這邊是昨天一樣繼續吃昨天的那個小菜
Preserved eggs with cucumber and self-made Taiwanese kimchi
就是小黃瓜皮蛋還有自己做的台式泡菜
And this is stir-fried vegetables I made today
然後這是今天炒的一堆蔬菜
This is radish ribs soup with meatball from yesterday
這是昨天的那個蘿蔔貢丸排骨湯
What a long name
好長的名字
Look, it's so pretty
然後你看很美
And this is the chicken cartilage that was air-fried just now
然後這個是剛剛氣炸的那個雞軟骨
Wow, it's so pretty. I want to show it to my mom.
哇很美 我要拍給我媽看
This rice
這個飯
Looks a lot like Taiwanese sticky rice
就長得很像油飯
So good
好好吃喔
Do you want to grab a spatula?
你要拿一個鏟子嘛
This rice is so delicious
這個飯太好吃了
Bento
便當
Look on the side
看旁邊
What are you doing?
你在幹嗎
I am going to make a super quick lunch now
我現在要來做一個超快速午餐
I'm very happy just thinking about eating this dish
然後這個是我我就是想到要吃它就會非常開心
Let me show you what I'm eating
給你們看一下我吃什麼
First, I heated some rice
首先呢我熱了一些飯
Some white rice and brown rice
就是有一半白飯有一半糙米飯
Because white rice is not enough
因為白飯不太夠
And then
然後
Yes, the key is this
對 然後重點是這個
This is seasoned radish
這個是一個那種seasoned radish
It's the kind of Korean pickled radish
就是那種醃的蘿蔔 那種韓式醃蘿蔔
I think this brand is
然後我覺得這個牌子是我吃過
From the three brands that I have eaten
我吃過大概三種這種醃蘿蔔
This is my favorite brand
然後這個是我最喜歡它的味道的牌子
It's so good with rice
然後它拌飯超級好吃
It's really delicious
就是真的很好吃
This is already the fifth box I bought
這已經是我買的可能有沒有第五盒之類的
It is sold at supermarkets or Weee
在一些超市或是Weee之類的都有賣
It looks like this
他長這樣
And then
然後
Basically
基本上呢
Just throw it in
就把它
Can you see?
你們看得到吼
It’s super simple. When I don't have much time to make lunch
超簡單 我每次像我今天沒什麼太多時間可以做午餐
I can quickly make this
我就會快速的拌飯
The key is that its juice is very thick and delicious
然後重點是他的汁就是是那種很濃很好吃的
I want to save a little bit for tomorrow
要留一點點
A little bit of sesame oil
一點點麻油
I usually add a little sesame oil to my rice
一般我拌飯都會習慣加一點麻油
The key ingredient is seaweed flakes
然後再來很重要的就是海苔酥
I'm adding the seaweed flakes from Bibigo
我這邊加的是那個bibigo的海苔酥
Depending on how much you want to add
看你們自己喜歡的量
I like to add a lot
我都加還蠻多的
Next step is to give it a good stir
再來就是拌飯好不好 把它拌好
When it's done it'll look super delicious
等一下拌好你們就會看起來為什麼那麼好吃
Give it a good stir
我把它攪拌
(Happy lunch time)
（開心的放飯時間）
Hi everyone, I am going to make dinner now
哈囉大家我現在要來準備晚餐
I'm going to continue making ribs for dinner today
今天晚餐呢我要再繼續做排骨
Because I defrosted a whole pack of ribs that day
因為我那天就是冷凍了的一個一整包大排骨
There are four big rows of ribs
然後裡面有四大條
I used three of them yesterday and the day before yesterday
然後我現在昨天跟前天用了三條嘛
So I will finish the last one today
所以我今天要再用最後一條
Besides the ribs, I plan to make dry noodles with sauce
除了排骨我打算做一個簡單
Then maybe just add some cucumbers, and some shredded eggs
然後可能就切一些什麼小黃瓜啊 就是切那種蛋絲
Mix it with the dry noodles with sauce and pork ribs
然後拌一拌 乾拌麵然後配排骨
And the leftover soup from the day before
然後喝前一天剩下的湯
I've had it for three days now and we need to finish it today
已經喝了三天 今天一定要把它喝完
I'm still debating
我還在猶豫 狗一直在看我
I'm still debating whether to air-fry the chicken cartilage like yesterday
我還在猶豫要不要氣炸昨天那個雞軟骨
Because it's pretty good
因為蠻好吃的然後
Let me see
我想想
I prepared some shredded chicken breast
我這邊準備了一些小小碎的雞
I'm using the... hold on
用的是那個 等我
I'm using this one from Costco
用的是這個 那個Costco的這個
They're in these pieces so I cut them smaller
我就把它 因為它是這樣一塊一塊的我就把它稍微切碎
I can throw them into the dry noodles with sauce later
然後等下可以丟在那個乾拌麵裡面
I also prepared a big pot of vegetables here
然後這邊準備了一大盆蔬菜
I'll just stir-fry it later
等一下就是把它炒一炒
So today’s diner includes soup and dry noodles with sauce
所以今天的菜有湯 乾拌麵
Stir-fry some vegetables with the pork ribs
然後炒一個蔬菜 跟排骨
This should be enough
這樣應該可以了
(Making the sauce for the dry noodles~)
（調乾拌麵醬汁～）
The key is the sesame seeds
靈魂是芝麻
After sprinkling on some sesame seeds, it looks more professional
撒上芝麻之後像一半嘛
Shredded egg
蛋絲
Chicken
這個肉
That chicken breast
用那個雞胸肉
Momoya Spicy Chili Sauce that I shared before
之前分享過的這個桃屋的辣椒
It's very fragrant but not spicy at all
很香然後完全不辣
I can use it up today
今天可以把它用完了
Dinner is ready
晚餐完成
For dinner today, we have a bowl of soba noodles
今天吃的是一個是蕎麥麵
And a bowl of white noodles because we don't have enough noodles
一個是乾麵 因為麵不太夠
Then vegetables
然後蔬菜
And this is the pickled preserved egg with cucumber from a few days ago
然後這是前幾天醃的那個小黃瓜皮蛋
Tea
茶
We need to finish this pork ribs soup quickly
趕快要把這個那個排骨湯喝完
I also made a new batch of honey braised pork ribs
然後新做了一份那個蜜汁排骨
I also added the chicken from Costco
我還把那個costco的那雞肉加進去
So smart
聰明吧
I want to add more chili
我加一點辣
I've been loving this chili powder recently
最近很愛這個辣椒粉
Almost
差一點
Good morning everybody
大家早安
It's almost half past seven in the morning
現在是早上的差不多七點半
I want to make some congee for breakfast today
然後我今天想要來做一個粥當早餐
(Shrimp, cabbage and salted egg congee) I am starving now and I want to eat a hot bowl of congee
（鮮蝦白菜鹹蛋粥） 我現在很餓然後就想要吃一個熱熱的粥
I just realized that my vegetables
我剛發現我的菜
Because the fridge is too cold, the vegetables have frozen
就是冰箱太冰了 它都結就是結這種冰塊
I'll cut some Chinese cabbage
我來切一點那個小白菜
The cabbage seems frozen
白菜好像凍僵了
I want to add salted eggs today
今天要加鹹蛋
I am in love with salted eggs recently
我最近超愛吃鹹蛋
A few days ago I even
我昨天 我前幾天還就是
I ate a salted egg when I had nothing to do in the afternoon
下午沒事然後開了一顆鹹蛋把它吃掉
The congee looks like this now
現在粥大概是這樣子
It should be ready in about two minutes
大概再差不多兩分鐘就可以了
Make it a little bit thicker
再讓他稠一點
I also added a little bit of cooked multigrain rice
我還加了一點那個已經經煮好的雜糧飯進去
I just cut the shrimp into small pieces
我剛切了蝦子就是把它切成小塊的
Like this
這樣
(Done) It looks super delicious
（完成） 看起來超好喝的
The spicy radish from yesterday
昨天那個辣蘿蔔
Is it in focus?
有對焦嗎
I can eat this again on the weekend
這個就可以周末早上的時候再熱來吃
Scared me
嚇死我了
OK
好拉
(It's so good! The salted egg added so much flavor) Wow, it's delicious with the salted egg
（很好吃！加鹹蛋很鮮） 哇 加鹹蛋很香
Added a little radish kimchi on top
順便加一點那個蘿蔔泡菜
I feel like I can add preserved eggs in next time
感覺下次也可以把皮蛋也加進去
I think preserved eggs and salted eggs will go really well together
就皮蛋加鹹蛋我覺得很好吃
It's been pretty hot here in the Bay Area
最近灣區這邊還蠻熱的
I'm mostly wearing short sleeves
我都穿短袖
Coffee
咖啡
Guava
芭樂
I'm going to cut it and eat it right after
我等一下就要來切來吃
I've been waiting for guava for a long time
等芭樂等好久
And a lot of Asian pears
還有超多水梨
What is this?
這是什麼
Nana it's your favorite Asian pear
娜娜是你喜歡的水梨
Hand pulled scallion pancake
手蔥抓餅
A bag of fresh noodle
然後還有一個生麵
And a bag of edamame
然後還有一個毛豆
Nana, what is this?
娜娜是什麼
What a beautiful guava
漂亮的芭樂
Asian pear and guava
水梨 還有芭樂
These two are my favorite fruits
這兩個都是我很喜歡的水果
Asian pear
水梨
So juicy
超水
Snack time
吃個零食
(Can't stop eating) I'm going to eat this taro pastry later
（一直吃） 等一下要吃這個芋頭酥
Is it in focus? Is it?
是不是沒有對焦 有對焦嗎？
This taro pastry
這個芋頭酥
I love the egg yolk pastry from the same brand
我覺得這個牌子的那個蛋黃酥很好吃
I haven't had their taro pastry before
我還沒有吃過他的芋頭酥
So pretty
很漂亮
Can you see?
看得到嗎？
Air-fry it for a bit
炸個
Smells so good
好香
It feels like there is a taro paste inside
它裡面感覺是有包一個芋泥
It's not overly sweet either
也不會太甜
Oh there's mochi inside
喔裡面是麻糬
The white thing
那個白白的
I feel that if you pair it with some hot tea
感覺如果配一點熱茶
Will go really well together
會非常酥
I finished it in one go
一下就吃完了
Elle
欸嚕
(Friday dinner - my friends came to our house for dinner)
（週五晚餐 朋友們來家裡一起吃）
(We ordered fried chicken + cooked instant ramen together)
（一起叫了炸雞＋煮泡麵吃）
(Thank you for watching, see you in the next video~)
（謝謝大家收看 下個影片見～）